Tom Hiatt

Metro Manila, National Capital Region, Philippines



hiattt@who.int



linkedin.com/in/tom-hiatt-8180b037

Summary

Experienced public health professional interested in eHealth, mHealth, infectious diseases, health emergencies, data visualization, country development, effective social interventions, social business/enterprise, and any other solutions that supplement limited resources to improve the lives of people everywhere.

Experience



Technical Officer, Tuberculosis

World Health Organization

Jun 2019 - Present (2 years +)

Support the National Tuberculosis Program of the Philippines Department of Health for all aspects of massive scale-up of screening, testing, treatment and prevention under the Race to End TB campaign. Develop and design the End TB App Suite (http://ntp.doh.gov.ph/apps). Monitor and mentor activities at the subnational level.

Support the National Rabies Prevention and Control Program with joint annual reports from the human and animal sectors, mapped and improved data flows, technical advisories, national vaccination campaigns, rapid response, and health promotion.



Monitoring And Evaluation Specialist, Health Emergencies

World Health Organization

Jan 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 6 months)

Monitoring, evaluation and analysis of trends in health emergencies across the 37 countries and areas of the WHO Western Pacific Region. Coordinate the implementation of information platforms and support progress monitoring of the International Health Regulations in countries.



Epidemiologist, Tuberculosis and Leprosy

World Health Organization

Jan 2012 - Dec 2016 (5 years)

Create and manage web-based systems for collection and storage of TB and leprosy data, analyse and report these data through annual reports and scientific publications. Develop electronic and mobile apps for health workers and members of national programmes for assessing disability, educating patients, accessing information and analyzing data. Coordinate, create and analyse tables and figures (including maps) for the annual Global TB control Report. Provide direct technical assistance to countries through national TB programme reviews, research studies and surveillance system assessments.



Health Data Analyst, Tuberculosis

World Health Organization

Jan 2007 - Jan 2012 (5 years 1 month)

Analyse burden of Tuberculosis (TB) disease to create tables and figures (including maps) to be included in the annual Global TB control Report (www.who.int/tb/publications/global_report). Coordinate and support web-based TB data collection system. Identify problems, improvements and assess usability of data management system. Workshop facilitation for regional TB estimates analysis and development. Conduct training on data analysis and exploration. Manage dissemination of TB data through web and print. Create interactive graphs, maps and tables. Design posters and displays for the World Health Assembly. Chair the Learning Working Group of the Health Data Forum (community of practice of data managers and analysts across WHO and other health agencies). Teach beginner's course on R statistical software. Manage software user groups.

Education

London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, U. of London

MSc, Epidemiology 2010 - 2013

Brigham Young University

BA, Visual art, Media art 2001 - 2005

Skills

R • Stata • Data Collection • Reports • Data Processing • Data Visualization • Epidemiology • Analysis • Global Health • Data Management